Shimin Rao

Washington, D.C. | 551-482-2902 | thunderous 0518@hotmail.com | LinkedIn | Github

Full Stack Software Engineer

I am an experienced developer with over 7 years of software development testing experience and strong database and troubleshooting skills. As a task-oriented programmer, I am passionate about uncovering, analyzing, and finding solutions for difficult problems. I consistently take on new challenges and learn technologies that allow me to work alongside high performing teams.

Skills:

- Java, C, Python, C#, VBA, JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- Spring, Hibernate, JDBC, Struts, Servlet, ¡Query, Node.js, Django, React, Express
- Oracle, SQL Server, MySql, MongoDB, PostgreSQL
- Tomcat, Eclipse, IntelliJ IDEA, Visual Studio, Git/Github, Docker, Maven, Jenkins
- Excellent troubleshooting skills—ability to analyze data, algorithms, code, and resolve issues quickly.
- Knowledge of RESTful, CICD, DevOps Concepts.

Experience:

Software Engineering Immersive | General Assembly | Washington, D.C. | Mar 2020 – Present Applied full stack developer skills in MVC framework to solve real-world business problems during a 500-hour course. Projects included:

- News Assistant: Created a full-stack application for users to search, view, create, edit, and delete the news. Used React, Node, Express, MongoDB, Javascript, HTML, CSS.
- Contact Book: Developed a command line application that allows users to search, view, create, edit and delete contacts. Used Python, PostgreSQL, Peewee, pipenv.
- Component Library: Created UI Component Library with React, Storybook, HTML, CSS.

Project Engineer | Industrial Securities Co., Ltd. | Shanghai, China | Jul 2010 – Aug 2013

- Partnered with 50+ financial analysts to gather and refine business requirements for Securities Research
 Platform. Discussed the requirements with financial analysts regularly to control the requirements and reduce
 development risk.
- Supervised Securities Research Platform's progress through project reports, ensured the system was delivered to business departments on time.
- Successfully built the second and third phase project of Securities Research Platform, resulting in improvement of the securities research team's new wealth ranking to seventh.
- Monitored system performance through backend support platform, ensured 1000+ report emails were automatically sent to other financial companies on time every day.

Software Developer | Sinitek Computer Technology Co., Ltd | Shanghai, China | Jul 2006 – Jun 2010

- Worked with business development and professional services teams, used visio to analyze the requirements, design, implementation, and delivery of a Securities Research and Knowledge Management Platform for financial analysts.
- Participated in 4 projects' development, implemented 4+ features (including analysis reports preparation, stock pool operation, task plans) based upon client requirements.
- Performed onsite support for 6+ clients, including onsite development, delivery, and system bugs fixes.
- Collaborated with QA team to troubleshoot system bugs/issues and provide fixes in a fast and efficient manner.

Education:

- Software Engineering Immersive | General Assembly | Washington, D.C. | 2020
- B.S. Computer Science and Technology | Huagiao University | China | 2006